Finding Aid for Catalogs of Michigan-based motor truck companies
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Catalogs of Michigan-based motor truck companies
1900-1946
undated
Bentley Historical Library.
EA 134 M919 C357
Collected material on motor trucks, carriages, and wagons produced by Michigan firms primarily between the years 1900 and 1935'
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was assembled from a variety of sources.
Periodic additions to the collection are expected.
The collection is open to research.
The Bentley Historical Library as a repository of Michigan-based materials has accumulated from different sources a collection of motor truck catalogs. These catalogs are an important source for the study of the development of the truck manufacturing industry in Michigan.
The trucks trade catalog collection consists of one box of material on motor trucks, carriages, and wagons produced by Michigan firms primarily between the years 1900 and 1935. It is comprised almost entirely of advertising brochures and trade catalogs with a heavy emphasis on mechanical specifications. the collection is arranged by company name.
Subjects:
Trucks--Catalogs.; Chevrolet Motor Car Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Chrysler Corporation--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Dodge Brothers--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Durant Motors, Inc.--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Electric Truck Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Fargo Motor Corporation--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Federal Motor Truck Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Ford Motor Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; General Motors Corporation--Catalogs.Catalogs.; General Motors Truck Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Geneva Wagon Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Grabowsky Power Wagon Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Graham Brothers--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Holson Motor Patents Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Hudson Motor Car Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; International Harvester Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; J.L. Clark Manufacturing Co.--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Martin-Parry Corporation--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Metropolitan Body Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Motor Wagon Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Packard Motor Car Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Rapid Motor Vehicle Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Reliance Motor Truck Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.; Reo Motor Car Company--Catalogs.Catalogs.
Genre Terms:
Trade catalogs--Connecticut--Bridgeport.; Trade catalogs--Illinois--Chicago.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Dearborn.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Detroit.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Lansing.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Owosso.; Trade catalogs--Michigan--Pontiac.; Trade catalogs--New York (State)--Geneva.; Trade catalogs--Pennsylvania--York.; Trade catalogs--Wisconsin--Oshkosh.
- Chevrolet - Ford
  - Chevrolet Motor Co. (and General Motors Corp. Chevrolet Motor Division), Detroit, Mich.
    - The utility truck, 1928 (Box 1)
    - The sedan delivery and light delivery, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Chevrolet express trucks, Undated (Box 1)
    - Chevrolet 1 1/2 ton stake trucks, Undated (Box 1)
    - New Chevrolet six-cylinder trucks, Undated (Box 1)
    - A sensational new truck, Undated (Box 1)
    - Newly designed commercial bodies with Chevrolet quality throughout, Undated (Box 1)
  - Chrysler Corp. (Fargo Motor Corp.), Detroit, Mich.
    - Advance information, Fargo modern delivery, Undated (Box 1)
    - Fargo, Undated (Box 1)
    - Fargo freighter, Undated (Box 1)
    - Weatherproof bodies for the Fargo freighter, Undated (Box 1)
    - New Plymouth commercial car, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Dodge Brothers (Graham Brothers), Detroit, Mich.
    - Graham Brothers trucks, Undated (Box 1)
    - Graham Brothers trucks, commercial cars and motor coaches, Undated (Box 1)
    - Dodge Brothers trucks, commercial cars and motor coaches, Undated (Box 1)
    - Dodge Brothers trucks, buses and motor coaches, Undated (Box 1)
    - Good news for truck owners, Undated (Box 1)
    - Dodge Brothers trucks 1 1/2 ton model F 31, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Dodge Brothers trucks 1/2 ton model UF 10, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Dodge Brothers announce-A new Dodge truck, Undated (Box 1)
    - Two advertising brochures (one in Spanish), Undated (Box 1)
    - New Dodge job-rated trucks, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Durant Motors, Inc., Flint, Mich.
    - New Rugby trucks built by Durant, Undated (Box 1)
  - Electric Truck Co., Detroit, Mich.
    - Trucking & delivery with electric power vehicles, Undated (Box 1)
  - Federal Motor Truck Co., Detroit, Mich.
    - Federal double-duty truck, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Federal tractor trucks, 1929 (Box 1)
    - Federal trucks salute the golden jubilee of the automobile industry, 1896-1946; 1946 (Box 1)
  - Ford Motor Co., Dearborn, Mich.
    - Three advertising brochures for Ford trucks, 1930-1931 (Box 1)
    - Ford V-8 trucks bring hauling costs down, Undated (Box 1)
    - Ford trucks, 1941 (Box 1)
- General Motors - REO
  - General Motors Truck Co., Pontiac, Mich.
    - The lowest-priced 2000 pound capacity six cylinder truck, 1928 (Box 1)
    - Eight advertising brochures for Buick and Pontiac trucks, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
    - Model AC-100 1/2 ton range, Undated (Box 1)
  - Geneva Wagon Co., Geneva, N.Y.
    - Commercial bodies, Undated (Box 1)
  - Grabowsky Power Wagon Co., Detroit, Mich.
    - Catalog, Undated (Box 1)
  - Holson Motor Patents Co., Grand Rapids, Mich.
    - The Gyroscope motor truck, Undated (Box 1)
  - Hudson Motor Car Co., Detroit, Mich.
    - Hercules better business bodies for the Dover truck, (Hercules Products, Inc., Evansville, Ind.), 1929 (Box 1)
    - Dover, the commercial super-six, Undated; 2 editions (Box 1)
    - Four advertising brochures, undated (Box 1)
  - International Harvester Co., Chicago, Ill.
    - Our pioneering days are not over..., 1946 (Box 1)
  - J.L. Clark Mfg. Co., Oshkosh, Wis.
    - Clark of Oshkosh finer truck bodies and cabs for Chevrolet, Undated (Box 1)
      (Wolfe Body Co., Detroit, Mich)
  - Martin-Parry Corp. (makers of truck bodies), York, Pa.
    - Martin-Parry bodies for the Whippet light delivery, Undated (Box 1)
    - Martin-Parry bodies for Chevrolet, Undated (Box 1)
    - Martin-Parry bodies for the Chevrolet light delivery and utility truck, Undated (Box 1)
    - New Martin-Parry dump bodies for Chevrolet, Undated (Box 1)
    - The new line of Martin-Parry bodies for the half-ton Chevrolet, Undated (Box 1)
    - Martin-Parry cab for Chevrolet chassis, Undated (Box 1)
  - Metropolitan Body Co., Bridgeport, Conn.
    - The new Metro complex cab, Undated (Box 1)
      (includes 4 loose photographs)
  - Motor Wagon Company of Detroit, Detroit, Mich.
    - Motor Wagon Detroit for delivery purposes, 1912 (Box 1)
  - Packard Motor Car Co., Detroit, Mich.
    - Commercial vehicles catalog, 1911 (Box 1)
    - The trail of the lonesome truck, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Rapid Motor Vehicle Co., Pontiac, Mich.
    - Catalog G, 1910 (Box 1)
    - Three advertisements, 1911 (Box 1)
  - Reliance Motor Truck Co., Owosso, Mich.
    - Catalog, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Reo Motor Car Co., Lansing, Mich.
    - Reo semi-trailers coordinated units, circa 1934 (Box 1)
    - Reo offers ..., Undated (Box 1)
    - Reo 12-15 passenger bus, Undated (Box 1)
    - The new Reo 2-3 ton speed wagon, Undated (Box 1)
    - The new Reo 2-4 ton truck, Undated (Box 1)
    - The new Reo 2-5 ton truck, Undated (Box 1)
    - Four advertising brochures, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Five advertising brochures, Undated (Box 1)